### Contact Us
    
    Take back control with a 7-day Social Media Reboot. Get tips from experts in the film.
    
    * Email\*
        
    * Demographic
        
        I am...?A concerned userA parentAn educatorA tech workerOther
        
    * Email Consent\*
        
         I’d like to get information for my Social Media Reboot and occasional updates on The Social Dilemma and other Exposure Labs productions.\*

    ### We knew you’d click this!
    
    Notifications like these offer an enticing loop of pleasure that can create an unconscious attachment to our devices.

Privacy Policy
==============

INTRODUCTION
------------

Exposure Labs is a film and impact production company. We believe in the transformative power of storytelling to change our world. Our work includes the production of original documentary films, the development of impact campaigns to support these films, and field-building efforts to support other storytellers and movement-builders in using film as a more effective tool for action and advocacy.

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) is intended to inform you about the data processing we undertake through the Exposure Labs and Exposure Labs’ productions websites, including The Social Dilemma, Chasing Ice and Chasing Coral.

This policy does not address our other personal data processing operations. Additional policies and procedures are in place to address those operations and we provide relevant information to data subjects and the point of data collection, or as required by law.

This Policy is subject to regular review. Subsequent updates and amendments will be documented below and communicated to data subjects where required.

DATA CONTROLLER
---------------

The data controller for data collected and processed in accordance with this Policy is Exposure Labs:

P.O. Box 18930

Boulder, CO 80308

Any questions regarding this Policy or any other data protection issue should be submitted via email to privacy@exposurelabs.com

WHAT WE PROCESS & WHY
---------------------

### WEBSITE

We use cookies on our website – these include essential and non-essential cookies. Any non-essential cookies are dropped on the basis of your consent. More information about the cookies we use is provided in the Cookie section below.  

### MAILING LIST & EMAILS

We send out newsletters to keep our network informed of our work and productions. On the basis of your consent, we collect your name and email address from you for this purpose. You can withdraw your consent at any time by unsubscribing to the mailing list through the link provided in our newsletters.

On the basis of our legitimate interest, we may also share your name and email with our email provider in order to send you communications about events you sign up to, if you make a donation to us, or where you engage with us, for example by making a pledge or offering to host a screening. You can opt-out of these emails at any time by unsubscribing through the link provided.

### EVENTS

We organise events from time to time, using SplashThat and other trusted platforms to manage RSVPs and ticketing. When you sign up for one of our events, we will direct you to the platform where, on the basis of your consent, we will collect your name and email address in order to issue you with a ticket.

### OUTREACH

For those looking to screen one of our films or host an event in conjunction with our impact campaigns, we collect names, contact and event details on the basis of consent. We use Gravity Forms to collect this information and to register these events.

If you sign up to our Environmental Voter Project, we collect your name, email, street address and phone number on the basis of your consent. We partner with the Environmental Voter Project (EVP) to collect this information. EVP updates us on new users who have taken this pledge, this is purely for impact analysis purposes and does not include any personally identifiable information.

### FUNDRAISING

To collect and manage donations, we partner with the Wild Foundation for Chasing Coral and the Denver Film Society for The Social Dilemma. If you make a donation you will be directed to the partner’s website and your name, contact details and payment information will be processed on the basis of your consent. Your information will be processed in accordance with our partners’ privacy policies, which are available here: [Wild Foundation Privacy Policy](https://www.wild.org/privacy-policy/), [Denver Film Society Privacy Policy](https://www.denverfilm.org/privacy-policy/). 

### ADVERTISING

We occasionally advertise through social media platforms like Facebook, but we do not use any information about individuals to target them.

### DATA RETENTION

In general, data will be retained for as long as is necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it was collected. Where data is collected on the basis of consent, we retain it until you withdraw your consent or otherwise when the data becomes no longer relevant for the purpose for which it was collected. Some data is retained in line with legal obligations on us, for example tax record keeping connected with making a donation, and it will be deleted at the end of the relevant period required by law.

### SENSITIVE DATA

Exposure Labs does not collect any sensitive data within the definition of EU data protection laws. As described above, we partner with EVP and collect data that indicates an individual prioritises the environment when voting, but this data only relates to US-based individuals and does not reveal political affiliations or opinions.

COOKIES
-------

Cookies are small files which are saved to your device in order to allow your device to be recognised by a website. We use cookies across our websites, some of these are necessary to allow the website to function, some allow us to track engagement with our audience. All non-essential cookies are deployed on the basis of your consent. The table below sets out the cookies we use:

### ESSENTIAL COOKIES

These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off or opted-out of.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Provider | Cookie | Purpose |
| socialdilemma.wpengine.com | cookielawinfo-checkbox-necessary cookielawinfo-checkbox-non-necessary | Determines whether the user has accepted the cookie consent box. |

PERFORMANCE COOKIES
-------------------

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our websites. They help us understand which pages are most or least engaged with and see how visitors move around the websites.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Provider | Cookie | Purpose |
| wpengine.com | \_ga, \_gat, \_gid | Google cookies used to register a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website and to throttle request rates. |
| google-analytics.com | collect | Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels. |

MARKETING COOKIES
-----------------

These cookies are set through our site by our advertising partners and may be used to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant ads on other sites. They don’t store directly personal information but they are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Provider | Cookie | Purpose |
| doubleclick.net | test\_cookie, IDE | Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking on advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user. Used to check if the user’s browser supports cookies. |
| youtube.com | visitor\_info1\_live, YSC, yt-remote-cast-installed, yt-remote-device-id, yt-remote-fast-check-period, yt-remote-session-app, yt-remote-session-name | We embed trailers through YouTube links. YouTube then sets cookies through our site that it us to estimate user bandwidth on pages with integrated videos, register a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen and store the user’s video player preferences using embedded YouTube video. |

**Opting in and out of cookies**
--------------------------------

When you visit our websites for the first time, a cookie consent box appears allowing you to provide your consent to non-essential cookies (opting-in) or to reject the cookies (opting-out). By default, non-essential cookies are disabled. You can access this box and opt-in or out at any time – it appears at the bottom of the page.

INFORMATION SECURITY
--------------------

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that personal data is processed securely and treated in accordance with this Policy. The technical and organisational measures to prevent unauthorised access to personal data include limiting staff and third party access to personal data in accordance with specific job responsibilities or contractual obligations, the encryption of data where possible, the institution of security protocols and staff training. Although we do our best to protect personal data, information transmitted over the internet remains vulnerable to interception – for this reason, the transmission of any personal data to our websites or via email to us is therefore at the data subjects’ own risk. 

**Data sharing, processors and international transfers of data**
----------------------------------------------------------------

We work with certain carefully-selected third party providers who process data on our behalf. These include MailChimp, Gravity Forms, SplashThat, Wild Foundation, Denver Film Society, Streak, Zapier, WordPress and others who provide content management systems and services that allow us to deliver our websites. We share data with these providers on the basis of our legitimate interests in delivering our productions and operating our websites, mailing lists and events. These providers have safeguards in place to ensure that data is protected and treated in compliance with international data protection laws and standards, including in relation to the international transfer of data.

****External websites****
-------------------------

Our websites include links to external websites which may process your data or use cookies – for example links to external resources and social media platforms. You can find out more about these services and their use of cookies through their respective websites and privacy policies. Please remember we cannot control the way those external websites collect and retain your personal data, so you use those external services at your own risk. 

****YOUR RIGHT****S
-------------------

Where EU data protection laws apply to individuals whose personal data is processed by Exposure Labs, the following rights are available:

* The right to be informed as to whether Exposure Labs holds data about them;
* The right of access to that information;
* The right to have inaccurate data corrected;
* The right to have their data deleted;
* The right to opt-out of particular data processing operations;
* The right to receive their data in a form that makes it “portable”;
* The right to object to data processing;
* The right to receive an explanation about any automated decision making and/or profiling, and to challenge those decisions where appropriate.

To make a request or complaint related to the processing of your personal data contact privacy@exposurelabs.com

Individuals covered by EU data protection laws may also be entitled to lodge complaints in regard to data processing or the handling of subject access requests with data protection supervisory authority in their country of residence. Relevant supervisory authority names and contact details are listed [here](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080).

CHANGES & REVISIONS
-------------------

This Policy may be updated from time to time. The date and nature of changes made will be listed below.

Policy published 11 September 2020.

Yes, we're on social. [Here's why](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/code-of-ethics/)

**The Social Dilemma** is a production of [Exposure Labs](https://www.exposurelabs.com/), a film and impact production company.

* Email\*
    
* Email Consent\*
    
     I’d like to receive updates about The Social Dilemma and Exposure Labs productions and I consent to my data being used in accordance with the Privacy Policy.\*

 [Arabic](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/ar/ "Arabic") [Chinese (Simplified)](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/zh-CN/ "Chinese (Simplified)") [Dutch](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/nl/ "Dutch") [English](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/ "English") [French](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/fr/ "French") [German](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/de/ "German") [Italian](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/it/ "Italian") [Portuguese](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/pt/ "Portuguese") [Russian](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/ru/ "Russian") [Spanish](https://www.thesocialdilemma.com/es/ "Spanish")

We value your privacy. Our use of cookies is strictly limited to those that help us understand how the site is being used. You can opt out of all tracking using our COOKIE SETTINGS link or click ACCEPT to provide this helpful feedback to our team.

Cookie settingsAccept AllReject

Cookies Policy

Close

#### Privacy Overview

This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.

Necessary

 Necessary

Always Enabled

Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.

Non Necessary

 non-necessary

Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.

Save & Accept
